RUCHITA SARDESAI



Professional Summary

An ISTQB Certified Quality Assurance Lead with more than 8.5 years of experience across multiple domains like Healthcare, Banking, Finance, and Retail specializing in both Automation as well as Manual Testing.



Work Profiles

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ruchita-sardesai-9323759b

GitHub: https://erruchita.github.io



Employment history

Quality Assurance Lead, TSYS- Mineraltree, Bangalore. (Promoted Twice)

Mar. 2018 – Present

- Lead the team to improve on their current capabilities through various cross training programs, thereby enabling them to upscale and deliver on both product and automation initiatives
- Implemented **on-boarding process** for new QA resources.
- Executed critical knowledge transfer and communication processes with all teams
- Initiated Automation(API) and docker pipeline for Totalpay product.
- Provided continuous review and recommendations for improvement of processes related to status reporting/dash-boarding and QA
- Developed **DevOps continuous integration** using Jenkins for test,pre-production.
- Promoted QA standards and best practices across Agile teams
- Closely worked on Python -BDD(API +UI), Locust, JMeter, Selenium webdriver
- Driven and contributed to the Manual and Automation test strategy, scripts, and framework focusing on test architecture, re-usability, stability, performance, scalability, and related Quality/team metrics
- Planned coverage projects from initiation through closer.
- Performed System, Integration, Regression, Functional, Database, Pen and Acceptance Testing on test and production server.
- Communicated the status of testing initiatives to the stakeholder groups and lead triage meetings.
- Primary point of contact for all quality aspects of releases
- Voluntarily **conducted** Thanksgiving days to help the team appreciating each other.

Test Analyst, Civica, Vadodara.

Jan. 2017 – Jan. 2018

- Implemented Automation Test Script using JMeter.
- Highly involved in Functional, Regression, API testing and Load testing.
- Key skills and achievements: Appreciated by the Project manager and Test lead of the project to crack complex logic for schedule overlapping. A key driver to automate/test the Payment Schedules and drawdown of this project.

Software Test Engineer, IHCS Technologies Pvt. Ltd. (Insync), Vadodara.

Mar. 2016 - Jan. 2017

- Developed **Selenium Automation Test Scripts** using Visual Studio 2013 in C#.
- Analyzed the functional requirements for Product (EHR and PM) from JIRA, TFS. Preparation of Manual Test Cases based on requirements and execution in TFS.
- Tested Web application, IOS and Android application of EHR and PM in relevant devices by executing test cases in TFS.
- A key driver of Root Cause Analysis / FMEA (Failure Mode Effect Analysis) of the product

Personal info

Phone:

9979258835

Email:

sardesairuchita@gmail.com

Location:

Bangalore

Skills

Domain:

US Healthcare, US&UK Payments, Financial Services, Retail

Automation | Testing Tools:"

Python, Locust, Selenium WD & IDP, JMeter, Postman, Burp Suite, HPQC/ ALM, UI Path, Swagger, WireShark, Fiddler, Kibana

Project Management Tools:

JIRA, Confluence, Test Rail, TFS, VSTS, Trello, ZOHO

Automation Testing

Framework:

Page Object Model (POM), BDD and Hybrid Framework with Python, C# and JAVA

Database: SQL, MYSQL, Azure

CosmosDB

Methodologies: Agile- Kaban & scrum, Waterfall

Types of Testing:

API, Integration, System, Regression, Smoke, Functional, Security, Pen, Load, Performance, Acceptance, Database Testing

Operating System:

Windows, Android, IOS

Key Interests: Dancing, Painting, Travelling, Cooking

Software Tester, HRP Software (Now Bluebox Infosoft Pvt Ltd.), Vadodara.

Nov. 2014 – Mar. 2016

- A key driver of Root Cause Analysis of the product.
- Tested web application, IOS and android Application of multiple projects.
- Highlighted key issues of the Accounts and Parts Modules in Deal Management System project.



Education

Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel Institute & Technology (SVIT), Gujarat

B.E (E&C), CGPA: 8.5, Jun. 2014

Reliance School, Vadodara

Higher Senior Secondary, 80%, Mar. 2010

Vidhya Vihar School, Vadodara

Senior Secondary, 88.85%, Mar. 2008



Certification

Product owner PSPO1 scrum Certification 2023- Udemy

Visharad (Bachelors) & Arangetral in Bharatanatyam, 2018

ISTQB International Certified Tester, License ITB-CTFL-0079679, 2015

ICTP -software testing, Innate Labs, License INL-CTP-60000500, 2014